<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Touch This Page! Making Sense of the Ways We Read</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Touch This Page! Making Sense of the Ways We Read</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>About Us &amp;ldquo;Touch This Page!&amp;rdquo; - An Introduction &amp;ldquo;Touch This Page! Making Sense of the Ways We Read&amp;rdquo; is an exhibition about multisensory experiences of reading. Its central objects are 3D replicas from historical books for blind and low-vision readers printed between 1830 and 1910. Most of these archival materials live at the Samuel P. Hayes Research Library at the Perkins School for the Blind. We hope that, by experiencing these 3D-printed objects, you will reflect on how touch, sight, and sound contribute to experiences of reading—historically and today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/panel1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/panel1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to &amp;ldquo;Touch This Page!&amp;rdquo; How are you reading these words?&#xA;Looking at a screen? Feeling braille? Listening to a voice?&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Touch This Page!&amp;rdquo; asks you to think differently about reading. Each station offers a 3D reproduction of a page in a style invented for sighted and blind readers in the 1830s and 1840s. Unlike braille, these pages of raised text use or lightly adapt the Roman alphabet to make the words more easily legible to visual readers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
